[music]
[Instructor] Okay, cool,
so we have our little character here,
happily jumping along through the forest,
and occasionally
that Obstacle comes through.
But we do have a larger problem,
where,
because we're making
it look like the character's running
through the woods, in fact,
it's our Background
that's running away
from our character.
So we need to figure out a way
that we can actually fix that,
and I have a little
bit of an idea.
So one thing that I could do
is actually,
if I select our Background,
and I Control + D to duplicate,
I can create another Background,
and then I can just keep creating
these Backgrounds over, and over again,
and then it'll just look like
the Player's running through.
However, that's probably one of the
worst ways that I could actually solve
this problem because then I'll
just have maybe, like,
50 or 100 of these Backgrounds
that are just constantly moving
all across the player.
And, eventually, they do run out
so I can't actually make that infinite,
and it'll actually
create some big problems for
making sure that
our game plays well
as it's trying to render all
of these different scenes
that are moving through the scene.
So another option is if
we delete this Background
because I don't think
that solution's
a very good idea at all. Another way
we could think about this problem
is we actually have
this Background here
and if you look at the halfway
point, just about there,
you can see that the Background
actually repeats itself,
so, it's got the same trees,
and it's got the same rocks at the end.
So we already have our own
little repeating Background.
And actually, we can think
of the problem in this way, where,
if you take a look
at the player's screen,
as we move the Background over,
just about at this point here,
it looks like the Background
is exactly the same.
And so what we can do is
precisely at this point,
we can actually just reset
our Background,
and it will look like the player,
is constantly running
through an endless Background
when in fact it's just these
two images next to each other
and we're just constantly
putting it overlapping each other
every single time we want it
to look the player's running.
So we're going to try,
and do it that way instead.
We're going to need a
Script in order to do so,
so we're going to right-click
on our Scripts Folder,
Create a new Script,
and we'll call this
RepeatBackground
in order to repeat
our Background.
And now with this Script,
we're going to drag
it and drop it,
onto our Background Object.
And then we're going to make
sure that it's applied.
So now you're going to go
into your Scripts Folder,
make a RepeatBackground Script,
and then you're going to
apply that Script
onto the Background.
Now it's your turn.
[music]